Guide to the William S. Burroughs Papers MSS.625
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III. Writing, 1968-2008; 11.81 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, and 1 folder in 1 shared flat box; 11 audiocassettes; 4.1 Megabytes in 434 computer files
  - Subseries III.G. Unpublished and Unrealized Projects, 1970-2008; 3.06 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes; 55.5 kilobytes in 2 computer files
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1970-1978 (Box 41, Folder 21-22)
    - Day to Day Diaries and Poems, 1978-1981 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1978-1981 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Day to Day and Dream Diaries, August-December 1981 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Day to Day Diaries, November 1981-January 1982 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Day to Day Diaries, December 1981-August 1982 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Day to Day Diaries, February-April 1982 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Day to Day Diaries, April-May 1982 and July-September 1984 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Day to Day Diaries, June-July 1982 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Day to Day Diaries, September-December 1982 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Day to Day Diaries, November-December 1982 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Day to Day Diaries, December 1982 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January 1983 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January-March 1983 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Day to Day Diaries ("Memoires"), January-May 1983 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Day to Day Diaries, February-March 1983 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Day to Day Diaries, March 1983 and March 1984 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Day to Day Diaries, March-April 1983 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Day to Day Diaries, April-May 1983 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Day to Day Diaries, April 1983, September-December 1983, and April 1984 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Day to Day Diaries ("Memoires"), June 1983 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Day to Day Diaries, June-July 1983 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Day to Day Diaries, August-October 1983 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Day to Day Diaries ("Art Notes"), 1983-1988 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January and November-December 1984 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Day to Day and Dream Diaries, April 1984 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Day to Day and Dream Diaries, April-December 1984 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Day to Day Diaries ("Dreams and Memoirs"), 1984-1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January 1985 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Day to Day Diaries, March-April 1985 and September 1986 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Day to Day Diaries, July 1985 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Day to Day Diaries, August 1985 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Day to Day Diaries, August-December 1985 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1985-1989 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Day to Day Diaries, February-March 1986 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Day to Day Diaries, March-June 1986 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Day to Day Diaries, September-December 1986 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Day to Day Diaries, November 1986-September 1987 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Day to Day Diaries, December 1986 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1986-1995 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Day to Day Diaries, May 1988-July 1989 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January-September 1988 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Day to Day Diaries, July-November 1988 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Day to Day Diaries ("Memoirs"), 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1988-1992 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Day to Day Diaries, January-September 1989 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Day to Day Diaries, June-October 1989 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Day to Day Diaries, September 1989 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1990-1994 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1991-1995 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1992-1993 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1992-1994 (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1993-1996 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 8-9)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Day to Day Diaries, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - "Dead Souls" and Other Writings, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Drug War", circa 1991 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - "Evil River" -- Notes and Possible Excerpt, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - "Five Shots H and R", April-May 1982 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - "His Last Christmas", January 1990 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "Immortality Unlimited" and Other Writings, 1984-1990 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "It Was 1948 or Thereabouts. Kells Elvins and I Was Raising Cotton…", February 1997 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "It Was Christmas Eve and Hyde…", circa 1992-1993 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "Kansas City", circa 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "The Man" -- Screenplay by David Ohle and Burroughs, circa 1994-1995 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "Miscellaneous Notes, Dreams", 1991 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Miscellaneous and Unassigned", 1986 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "The Monkeys Head", undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Mottos, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Naropa Institute Readings, August 1979 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Naropa Institute Readings -- Jack Kerouac Conference and Others, 1982-1983 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "No Immediate Use", 1985-1989 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "A Note on Drug Hysteria" and Other Writings, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Dennis Cooper's Closer, March 1991 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Novel in Progress Concerns Jesus Christ", 1980-1986 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "Octopus", 1989-1992 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "The Old Chateau" and Other Writings, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Paradise Lost -- Notes and Synopses for Opera, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Planet Venus", 1970-1979 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Poems, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Presidential Speech" and Reading Material, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Reading Material, 1980-1983 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Reading Material, August 1982-October 1983 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Reading Material, October-December 1982 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Reading Material, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Reading Material, circa 1982-1984 (Box 45, Folder 23-24)
    - Reading Material, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Reading Material, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Reading Material, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Reading Material, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Reading Material, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Reading Material, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Reading Material -- Kansas City Reunion, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - River City Reunion and AIDS Benefit Readings, 1986-1987 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "Scraps and Pictures", 1988 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Songs, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - "Special Items", circa 1980 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Tangier Text -- First Draft, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Target Notes", 1982 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Terra Nova Reading, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Text for Ritz Performance ("Arizona"), 1981 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - "Tribute to American Forebears" Contribution, February 1997 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "The Troughs", 1982 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Unrealized Book Project with Peter J. Swales -- Correspondence and Lists, 1992-2008 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1976-1979 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1982-1983 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1982-1985 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1982-1988 (Box 46, Folder 21-22)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 23-24)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1984-1989 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Untitled Manuscripts, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Untitled Manuscripts and Notes, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Vancouver, Seattle, and Portland Readings, July 1988 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "The Virginian" -- First Draft, September 1995 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - "The Whole Tamale", circa 1978 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - "Wild Boys" -- Film Treatment by Burroughs and James Grauerholz, March 1986 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - "The Wild Party" -- Draft, February 1993 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - "The Wishing Machine", November-December 1985 and March 1986 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Writing on AIDS, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Writing on Guns and Gun Ownership, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Writing on Paul Bowles and Arthur Chase, 1991-1992 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - "WSB Text for PL", September 1993 (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Series IV. Artwork, 1975-1997; 2.21 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in 1 shared flat box
  This series consists mainly of painted file folders, a few sketches, and targets from a firing range. Also included are Burroughs' artist CV and exhibition announcements, catalogs, and a poster. In most cases, painted file folders were retained with their original contents. In instances where the original contents were deaccessioned, painted file folders were moved to this series.
  - Early Artwork -- Self-Portrait and Mayan Drawings -- Photocopies, undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - "Easter Island" -- Photocopy, circa 1988 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - "Entrance to Museum of Extinct Species" -- File Folder Painting, undated (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalog, 1988-1993 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition History -- CV, 1990 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Poster, 1995 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 8)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1975-1985 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1986-1994 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1989-1991 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1991-1992 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - File Folder Paintings, circa 1993-1997 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - File Folder Paintings, undated (Box 47, Folder 26-28, Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - File Folder Paintings -- Photographs, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Handprints, circa 1981-1986 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - "James Grauerholz" -- File Folder Painting, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Mouse on Newspaper -- Color Prints, circa 1994 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Sketches and Doodles, circa 1989-1992 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Targets, circa 1981-1992 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - "The Umbrella" -- File Folder Painting, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - "The Ten Commandments" -- Proposal, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - "What Happened on the Mary Celeste?" -- Color Printout, circa 1988 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Works on Paper, circa 1983-1993 (Box 48, Folder 12)
- Series V. Events and Publicity, 1970-1998; 2.5 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 folders in 2 shared flat boxes; 310 kilobytes in 11 computer files
  This series mostly consists of materials related to Burroughs' participation in public events, such as readings and lectures. Materials include event announcements (posters, flyers, and advertisements), correspondence, clippings and other press, and production schedules. Also included are materials related to The Final Academy, a four-day multimedia festival in England organized by Genesis P-Orridge and others in 1982. Materials include programs, schedules, tickets, and reviews. This series also contains materials related to Ted Morgan's biography of Burroughs, Literary Outlaw: The Life and Times of William S. Burroughs (1988); materials such as correspondence, notes, FOIA files from the FBI, archival files from Time, and transcripts of interviews with Burroughs are included.
  - Event Listings and Press, 1978-1998 (Box 48, Folder 13-15, Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 8)
  - Event Poster, circa 1970-1979 (Box Shared Fales 122, Folder 10)
  - The Final Academy
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1982-1988 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Press Release, Advertisement, and Tickets, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Program and Schedules, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Reviews, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Literary Outlaw: The Life and Times of William S. Burroughs by Ted Morgan
    - Contracts, 1985-1986 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1982-1991 (Box 48, Folder 21-23)
    - Press and Publicity, 1985-1991 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Research Material from the CIA, FBI, and Time, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts of Burroughs' Interviews
      - Electronic Transcripts, 1990-1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_16
      - Paper Transcripts, 1984-1985 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Naropa Institute Writing Program, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - U2 Video Shoot, May 1997 (Box 49, Folder 5)
- Series VI. Subject Files, 1749-2006; 3.08 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in 1 shared flat box; 66 kilobytes in 1 Word document
  This series includes printed material (articles, clippings, journals, and catalogs) on various topics of interest to Burroughs. Many of these topics, such as firearms, animals, drugs, and the occult, were frequent subjects of his writing. Additional subjects covered include the Illuminates of Thanateros and UFOs. Also included is writing by other authors (such as David Ohle and Spencer Kansa).
  - Aboriginal Boomerangs, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - AIDS, 1986 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Alcoholism, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Anarchy: A Journal of Desire Armed, Winter 1995 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Animal Shelters, 1986-1996 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Animals, 1975-1998 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Artwork by Unidentified Artists, circa 1983-1986 (Box 49, Folder 12, Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 9)
  - Ballard, J.G., 1985 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Biosphere II, 1987-1992 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Blount, Roy, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Bowden, Tom -- "William S. Burroughs as 'American Scholar'", circa 1987 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Breakthrough: The Newsletter of Innovation, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Cats, 1987-1994 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Conspiracy Theories, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Count of Mirabeau, undated (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Demon Imagery, undated (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Dick Tracy, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Drug Traffickers, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Drugs, 1978-1997 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Earthquakes, 1986 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Ewert, Mark and Kevin Killian -- "Secret Garden", undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Fair and Circus Images -- 13th-19th Centuries, undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Film, 1980-1990 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Gambling, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Gay Rights, 1992-1994 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Genet, Jean, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Goldberg, Jeffrey -- Writings By, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Gruesome Deaths, 1990-1995 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Guardian Angels, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - The Harvard Medical School Health Letter, 1984-1989 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Hathaway, Michael -- "Cecil", circa 1991 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Health and Medicine, 1982-1996 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Heaven and Hell Images -- 16th-19th Centuries, undated (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Hisardut, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Holden, Roger -- "3D Pyramid Scheme", 1994 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Hudson, Patrick -- "The Persistence of Memory", undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - "I, Spastic", undated (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Illuminates of Thanateros, 1993-1995 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Jesus Christ, undated (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Joyriding, undated (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Kansa, Spencer -- "Kim Carsons: A Mythic Western", 2006 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Lie Detector Tests, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Loompanics Unlimited Book Catalogs, 1983-1996 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - The Mary Celeste, undated (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Maugham, Robin and W. Somerset, undated (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Mayas, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Men's Liberation Movement, 1982 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - New Age Movement, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - Nusbaum, Arthur S. -- "Kerouac Meets Burroughs On the Road", 1994 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - The Occult, 1987-1994 (Box 51, Folder 1-3)
  - Ohle, David -- Writings By, 1992
    - "Crank Calls" Scene 1 and "The Mortified Man" (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "Crank Calls" Scene 2, FA_MSS_625_ER_17
  - Orgonauts -- Publications, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Plane Crashes, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Police Brutality, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Psychiatry, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Religion, 1990 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Resistance Movements, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Revenge, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Roehl, Joseph Clay -- "Poisons in Our Midst", undated (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Schnabel, Julian, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Science, 1966-1985 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Scientology, 1965-1980 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Sex and Pornography, 1981-1996 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    Content Warning: Many of the images in this file are sexually explicit.
  - Shark Attacks, undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Shih, Daphne B.H., 1987 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Skateboarding, undated (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Skerl, Jennie -- "The Wild Boys: The Demonology of William S. Burroughs", 1982 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Spirit of Crazy Horse: Newsletter of the Leonard Peltier Defense Committee, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - SpyLetter -- Vol. 2, #1, undated (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - "Street Kids" -- Tijuana, Mexico, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - Subpoena Serving, undated (Box 51, Folder 25)
  - Sukenick, Ronald -- "The Crisis in Publishing", undated (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - Sukenobu Prints, 1749 (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Tabloids, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 28)
  - Terminal City Publications -- "A Dada Political Manifesto", undated (Box 51, Folder 29)
  - Torture Devices -- Ancient Egyptian Times-19th Century, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Transcendental Meditation, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - UFOs and Extraterrestrials, 1988-1994 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - "Uncle Zagnut Blows Up", undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - "The Village of the Dead: A Folktale", undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - "Vivisection", 1992 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Weapons, 1960-1994 (Box 52, Folder 7-8)
  - Weber, Bruce -- "Untitled", 1991 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Whistleblowers, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Windhausen, Wolfgang, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Wojnarowicz, David, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Writing by Unidentified Authors, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 13)